Clanker City! The big smoke! The city of ten thousand gears!
One small maintenance-bot, one dream, and not so much as an oil can to my name.
Thanks for the ride! I'll catch the return ferry once I'm rich and famous.
...
That clunk sounded expensive.
That clunk sounded PERMANENT.
WELCOME TO CLANKER CITY. POP. 8,01,1.
Population eight-oh-one-comma-one. The punctuation died first.
Maybe a good honest whack will fix the display.
It rained a bolt. In this town that's basically a tip.
One bolt. Only eight thousand and ten more and I can afford a personality upgrade.
Salt water and burnt transmission fluid. The smell of adventure!
Official city notice, hot off the press:
'DYNAMO MAINTENANCE: NOTHING IS WRONG. NOTHING HAS EVER BEEN WRONG.'
'DO NOT STOCKPILE OIL. SIGNED, MAYOR PISTON.'
The Great Dynamo powers every bot on this island. Including me, as of today.
So that notice is the scariest thing I've ever read.
Let me read it first. I'm a maintenance-bot, not a barbarian.
Hello up there! Lovely evening!
...
Bolted from the inside. The GOOD kind of bolted. I respect the craftsmanship.