Clanker City! The big smoke! The city of ten thousand gears!
One small maintenance-bot, one dream, and not so much as an oil can to my name.
Thanks for the ride! I'll catch the return ferry once I'm rich and famous.
...
That clunk sounded expensive.
That clunk sounded PERMANENT.
WELCOME TO CLANKER CITY. POP. 8,01,1.
Population eight-oh-one-comma-one. The punctuation died first.
Maybe a good honest whack will fix the display.
It rained a bolt. In this town that's basically a tip.
One bolt. Only eight thousand and ten more and I can afford a personality upgrade.
Official city notice, hot off the press:
'DYNAMO MAINTENANCE: NOTHING IS WRONG. NOTHING HAS EVER BEEN WRONG.'
'DO NOT STOCKPILE OIL. SIGNED, MAYOR PISTON.'
The Great Dynamo powers every bot on this island. Including me, as of today.
So that notice is the scariest thing I've ever read.
Let me read it first. I'm a maintenance-bot, not a barbarian.
Hello up there! Lovely evening!
...
A player piano, playing itself. It's missing three keys.
...That feels thematically significant.
I lean in casually. Extremely casually. Nobody has ever leaned this casually.
The one in the hat says: you CLANG twice, then once, then twice, you barnacle.
I am definitely not supposed to know that.
Token on the rail. Game on.
Dart one: the wall.
Dart two: a different wall.
Dart three is in the ocean. We're indoors. Nobody knows.
Flange is laughing so hard he goes for the showboat finish: three darts, one throw, behind the back.
His shoulder servo overheats with a noise like bacon achieving liftoff.
House rules: the overheated party forfeits the wager. The oil can is mine.
Losing this badly took real skill. Nobody will ever believe that.
Her joints are dry as a tax form. She needs oil before she'll move that crate.
It's twenty feet up. My arms are stock parts.
Betty could set it down, if anyone gave her a drink of oil.
The lid argues. I argue back with a plank.
Rivet's the name, he says. Knows everything. First fact's free:
The funicular to Midtown takes ten bolts. Exact change. Gates can count — it's all they do.
Second fact costs a bolt. He can see I don't have one. He mentions that for free too.
Third freebie, out of pity: the harbor keeps everything this town drops, and that dumpster is — legally — his.
Someone sprayed DYNAMO IS FINE. Crossed out. Under it, smaller: IT IS NOT.
Under that, very small: NO REFUNDS. The whole town, one wall.
Knock knock.
The slot opens. The same eye as the tavern. 'This is the BACK back door. STILL Act Three, buddy.'
This organization has remarkable message discipline.
Inside: one rubber duck, seized. One manual for a better game. And a magnet on a string.
In a town held together by bolts, a magnet on a string is a license to print money.
My fingers are factory-standard. I'd need something magnetic. On a string.
Rivet's the name, he says. Knows everything. First fact's free:
The funicular to Midtown takes ten bolts. Exact change. Gates can count — it's all they do.
Second fact costs a bolt. He can see I don't have one. He mentions that for free too.
Third freebie, out of pity: the harbor keeps everything this town drops, and that dumpster is — legally — his.
Nine bolts, I tell him. He appraises my pockets from four feet away. Correctly.
He proposes a riddle duel. His bolt against my official city notice. The alley has rules, apparently.
Ten bolts in the hopper. It counts them twice. Trust died in this town years ago.
The gate ratchets up, and a little brass car rolls down to meet me, lit up like a promise.
Act Two. I can hear the neon from here.
Gate's open, car's lit. Midtown keeps glittering like it doesn't know I'm coming.
Act Two will still be uptown tomorrow. Probably. If the Dynamo holds.
Ten bolts in the hopper. It counts them twice. Trust died in this town years ago.
The gate ratchets up, and a little brass car rolls down to meet me, lit up like a promise.
Act Two. I can hear the neon from here.
The fare box wants ten bolts. I have pockets, and ambition.
Talent night, tonight, he says. Grand prize: an oil voucher and a backstage pass.
Backstage. Where Madame Voltina reads fortunes. And guards... things. He doesn't say what things.
Sign-up needs a stage name and an act. I have a name, and a key the size of my forearm.
He says, quote, that's more act than most.
The Great Dynamo, up the hill, behind a fence with opinions.
Every bot on this island runs on that hum. Including me. The hum is flat by half a step.
Half a step doesn't sound like much. Neither does a clunk, until it's PERMANENT.
City Hall. The banner says NOTHING IS WRONG. It's brand new.
They replaced the old banner. The old one said the same thing, smaller.
An aide opens the door exactly nine degrees. The Mayor is not seeing anyone.
Especially, he adds, anyone holding paper.
There it is. SPROCKET. On a marquee. In lights.
Two of the bulbs are out. It still feels like destiny.
Talent night. Tonight. No pressure. The marquee is the pressure.