Clanker City! The big smoke! The city of ten thousand gears!
One small maintenance-bot, one dream, and not so much as an oil can to my name.
Thanks for the ride! I'll catch the return ferry once I'm rich and famous.
...
That clunk sounded expensive.
That clunk sounded PERMANENT.
WELCOME TO CLANKER CITY. POP. 8,01,1.
Population eight-oh-one-comma-one. The punctuation died first.
Maybe a good honest whack will fix the display.
It rained a bolt. In this town that's basically a tip.
One bolt. Only eight thousand and ten more and I can afford a personality upgrade.
Official city notice, hot off the press:
'DYNAMO MAINTENANCE: NOTHING IS WRONG. NOTHING HAS EVER BEEN WRONG.'
'DO NOT STOCKPILE OIL. SIGNED, MAYOR PISTON.'
The Great Dynamo powers every bot on this island. Including me, as of today.
So that notice is the scariest thing I've ever read.
Let me read it first. I'm a maintenance-bot, not a barbarian.
Hello up there! Lovely evening!
...
A player piano, playing itself. It's missing three keys.
...That feels thematically significant.
I lean in casually. Extremely casually. Nobody has ever leaned this casually.
The one in the hat says: you CLANG twice, then once, then twice, you barnacle.
I am definitely not supposed to know that.
Token on the rail. Game on.
Dart one: the wall.
Dart two: a different wall.
Dart three is in the ocean. We're indoors. Nobody knows.
Flange is laughing so hard he goes for the showboat finish: three darts, one throw, behind the back.
His shoulder servo overheats with a noise like bacon achieving liftoff.
House rules: the overheated party forfeits the wager. The oil can is mine.
Losing this badly took real skill. Nobody will ever believe that.
Her joints are dry as a tax form. She needs oil before she'll move that crate.
It's twenty feet up. My arms are stock parts.
Betty could set it down, if anyone gave her a drink of oil.
The lid argues. I argue back with a plank.